Jarhead: Law of Return is a war film directed by Don Michael Paul.
Major Ronan Jackson, an accomplished fighter pilot for the
Israel Defense Forces and son of a U.S.
Senator, is shot down while flying through Syrian airspace.
After miraculously surviving the crash, Jackson is taken
captive by a group of Hezbollah militiamen.
A squad of elite soldiers, led by Gunnery Sergeant Dave Torres, risk their
own lives in the hopes of saving an ally they've never met.
Ronan Jackson, played by Devon Sawa.
Neta Lurie, played by Yael Eitan.
Benedetti, played by Nicholas Aaron.
USMC General Betz, played by Ben Cross.
Sergeant Dave Flores, played by Amaury Nolasco.
Senator Jackson, played by Robert Patrick.
Jarhead is a 2005 biographical war drama film based on the 2003 memoir of the same name by Anthony Swofford,
chronicling his military service in the United States Marine Corps during the Persian Gulf War.
Directed by Sam Mendes, the film stars Jake Gyllenhaal as Swofford with
Jamie Foxx, Peter Sarsgaard, Lucas Black, and Chris Cooper.
Universal Pictures released the film November 4,
2005 to mixed reviews from critics.
It was a box-office disappointment, grossing $97
million against a $72 million budget.
Named for the military slang among U.S.
Marines, the film spawned a direct-to-video series of three
subsequent films, none of which are related to the original.